# CHETHAN MYSURU RADHAKRISHNA

#### Pursuing Master's in Data and Knowledge Engineering

- @ chethanmr.2694@gmail.com
- **J** +49 17636817295
- Arnold-Zweig Strasse 4, 39120, Magdeburg, Germany
- Magdeburg, Germany
- www.homepage.com in https://www.linkedin.com/in/chethan-radhakrishna-94310010b/
- https://github.com/chethanMysore



## **ABOUT ME!**

I am a data science enthusiast with an inclination towards visual exploration of trends in data. I am also a skilled web developer with a collective experience of 4 years. However, I believe in the idea that "What we know is a drop and what we don't know is an ocean".

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Developer

#### **Metratec Gmbh**

June 2019 - Ongoing

Magdeburg

Working as a full stack web developer. Handled API integration with react-redux dashboards. worked on real time data using web sockets. worked on event sourcing and reSolve(a CQRS framework built using node.js). Managed Gitlab pipeline and docker configurations with yaml.

#### Software Engineer

#### **Happiest Minds Technologies Pvt Ltd**

October 2016 - January 2019

Contributed as a full stack web developer. Worked on ASP.NET MVC applications and Web API services built on .NET framework 4.6.2 and .NET core. Worked on react.js and redux to implement stateful frontend designs. Worked exclusively on Health Care domain with the knowledge of online data exchange standards such as HL7. Worked on AWS EC2, S3 buckets, Simple Mail Service and Lambda(for deploying micro services). As a billable resource, interacted with clients to understand requirements and effectively communicated the innovative ideas to solve their problems.

#### **PROJECTS**

Interpretable Machine Learning to Understand Participant Evolution in Longitudinal Cohort Study Data

#### Otto-von-Guericke University

October 2019 - March 2020

The project aims at identifying evolutionary trends in longitudinal cohort data of a German population in Pomerania. The study focuses on explainable AI to explore the results of a machine learning model to derive critical factors influencing the diagnosis of Hepatic Steatosis. Worked on pre-processing, R-API development and visualization of model results using react-redux dashboard.

Technologies Used: R, react.js, redux, saga, canvas.js(for interactive graph visualizations)

## **EDUCATION**

M.Sc. in Data and Knowledge Engineering

Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg

**2019 - 2022 (Ongoing)** 

#### Coursework:

- Data Mining
- Machine Learning
- Information Retrieval
- Introduction to Deep Learning
- Distributed Data Management
- Data Management for Engineering Applications
- Visual Analytics

B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering

Vidyavardhaka College of Engineering, India

**2012 - 2016** 

## SKILLS

**Programming: Python Javascript** React.js C# SQL mongoDB Libraries: Scikit-Learn Keras Tensorflow

Pipelines: NLTK

spaCy

gensim

# Gesture Recognition For Interactive Systems Using Kinect V2

#### Vidhyavardhaka College of Engineering

iii November 2015 - April 2016

Developed a WPF application to recognize user gestures using Microsoft Kinect V2 sensor. The application binds different mouse and keyboard inputs to gestures performed by users and thereby allowing them to interact with the system. Authentication of users is performed with face recognition algorithm developed using PCA(Principal Component Analysis) to compare grey scale images of faces.

Technologies Used: .NET framework 4.5, WPF, Kinect V2 SDK, C#

IDEs: V	'isual Studio Eclipse Jupyter
Google	Colab
Version (	Control and CICD: Git Lab TFS
Octopu	Jenkins Docker

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Articles

Chethan M R Adarsh M V Akarsh M S Karunesh Gurkar, Prashanth Kumar (Guide) (2016). "Gesture Recognition for Interactive Systems Using Kinect v2". In: International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer and Communication Engineering (IJIRCCE), 4(5):9186-9191, 05 2016. ISSN: 2320-9801. DOI: 10.15680/IJIRCCE.2015.0405108.

## **LANGUAGES**

English		• •	
Kannada	•	• •	• •
Hindi	•	• •	• •
German		• •	• •

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**



'Individual Excellence Award' for outstanding contribution to the project and customer happiness.



'Mindful Egg Head Award' for demonstrating good composure and interpersonal skills.



Won 3rd place in the technical project exhibition, 'Vivacious-E16' held at Vidhyavardhaka College of Engineering